### **SUMMARY**

Web Developer with 10 years of experience using and developing for content management systems. Diverse development skills include: PHP, mySQL, JavaScript, HTML, server administration, shell scripting, among others. Developed successful products for the Joomla CMS market. Efficient and productive employee, experienced in Agile Development processes.

- PHP, mySQL, JavaScript, CSS, HTML
- Creative problem solver
- Node.is, NoSQL
- Server security, Application security
- · CDNs and server caching

- Server Administration
- Shell scripting
- · APIs, Mashups
- · Titanium, Mobile applications
- Fluent in English and Spanish

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Barracuda Networks, Inc., Ann Arbor, MI

2013-Present

Worldwide leader in Security, Application Delivery and Data Protection Solutions.

### Software Engineer, 2013 – Present

Worked on the Web Team for the Backup product.

- Maintained the website for the Backup product by fixing bugs and adding features.
- Responsible for solving low-level programming problems.
- Promptly solved issues for customers when they were escalated.
- Developed a solution to stream zip files to the browser.

# 'corePHP', Battle Creek, MI

2008-2013

'corePHP' is known for providing quality products and services throughout the Joomla! industry.

### Lead Developer, 2010 – Present

Responsible for overseeing all development jobs that passed through the company. Created complex web applications for the Joomla and WordPress CMSs, such as ecommerce applications, back-end systems, software integrations. Developed PHP with OOP and MVC architectures.

- Developed API mashups with AWS, Facebook, Twitter, Google, SalesForce.
- Implemented Agile Development processes.
- Taught PHP and Joomla sessions at expos.
- Developed systems to automate in-house processes.

### **PHP Developer**, 2008 – 2010

PHP Developer, focused on developing Joomla extensions for clients.

- Developed WordPress for Joomla, jomCDN, JPhoto and jomDefender.
- Worked on Digital Menu Board back-end system.

Rafael Corral Page Two

## **EDUCATION / TRAINING**

Network Security, Technology
Davenport University, Grand Rapids, MI
2006–2008

Information and Computer Security, Technology
Davenport University, Grand Rapids, MI
2006–2008

### ADDITIONAL RELEVANT INFORMATION

Developed jomMobile for Joomla – Mobile application to manage your Joomla website.

Speaker at CMS Expo – http://www.cmsexpo.net/speakers/1-102-Rafael\_Corral Speaker at Calhoun Area Career Center Speaker at technology events in the area